<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>Lorena Ciutacu</title>
    
    
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>How use math equations in Docusaurus</title>
        <description>
          
          One of the challenges I encountered when moving my website from Jekyll to Docusaurus was rendering math equations in some of my blog posts (for example, about the apriori algorithm). In Jekyll, I used MathJax with Liquid to render them. This didn’t work in Docusaurus, so instead I had to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/mathjax-katex/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/mathjax-katex/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to connect Google Sheets with MySQL</title>
        <description>
          
          If you’ve been struggling to connect your MySQL database with Google Sheets, you’ve come to the right place. Establishing a connection from Google Sheets to MySQL allows you to avoid manually updating data in one source and importing/exporting data sets, thus reducing human errors. Connecting Google Sheets with MySQL is...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/connect-mysql-sheets/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/connect-mysql-sheets/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to automatically import JSON into Google Sheets</title>
        <description>
          
          JavaScript Object Notation (JSON) is a standard text-based format that is used to store and represent structured data. JSON is commonly used in web applications, and is one of the most popular API formats. Data in JSON format is not practical if you want to share that data in a...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/import-json-spreadsheet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/import-json-spreadsheet/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to automate database activity monitoring and alerting</title>
        <description>
          
          Database activity monitoring (DAM) is increasingly valued in organizations that work with data, as it helps ensure that mission-critical processes run optimally and issues are detected on time. Established and new companies are offering a variety of DAM tools and solutions, tailored to the needs of customers across industries. The...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/database-activity-monitoring/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/database-activity-monitoring/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resources for technical writers</title>
        <description>
          
          For over a year now, I’ve been working as a technical writer in a tech startup developing a workflow automation tool. I’ve been part of a Developer Relations (DevRel) team, then a Marketing team, as well as some Product in-between. This organization means that I had to (re)learn how to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/resources-technical-writers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/resources-technical-writers/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to scrape data from a website with n8n</title>
        <description>
          
          It’s no secret (anymore) that data is precious. Structured data is particularly valuable for companies and professionals in pretty much any industry, as it offers them the raw material for making predictions, identifying trends, and shaping their target audience. One method for getting hold of structure data, that has been...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/webscraping-workflow/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/webscraping-workflow/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Webhooks explained</title>
        <description>
          
          Since being introduced in 2007, webhooks have revolutionized the web. These user-defined callbacks made it possible to access real-time data from an app, creating new infrastructure and opening up endless possibilities for web developers. In this post, you’ll learn the basics about webhooks: what they are, how they work, how...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/webhooks-explained/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/webhooks-explained/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Portugiesisches Gift von Luis Sellano</title>
        <description>
          
          Titel: Portugiesisches Gift Autor: Luis Sellano Verlag: Heyne Erschienen: April 2022 Seitenanzahl: 304 Bewertung: 🌕🌕🌗🌑🌑 Danke an Random House Bloggerportal und Heyne Verlag für die freundliche Bereitstellung dieses Rezensionsexemplars. Klappentext Ein Sommertag in Lissabon. Die Menschen flanieren durch die Altstadt, das Wasser des Tejo glitzert in der Sonne. Kriminalkommissarin Helena...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buchrezension-portugiesisches-gift/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buchrezension-portugiesisches-gift/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nachts im Internet von Stephen Law</title>
        <description>
          
          Titel: Nachts im Internet Autor: Stephen Law Verlag: Goldmann Erschienen: April 2022 Seitenanzahl: 240 Bewertung: 🌕🌕🌗🌑🌑 Danke an Random House Bloggerportal und Goldmann Verlag für die freundliche Bereitstellung dieses Rezensionsexemplars. Klappentext Jeden Tag suchen Millionen von Menschen bei Google Antworten – auf die kleinen, alltäglichen und auf die großen Fragen...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/nachts-im-internet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/nachts-im-internet/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Der Hauptmann und der Mörder von Zhou Haohui</title>
        <description>
          
          Titel: 18/4 - Der Hauptmann und der Mörder Autor: Zhou Haohui Verlag: Heyne Erschienen: Januar 2022 Seitenanzahl: 400 Bewertung: 🌕🌕🌕🌕🌑 Danke an Random House Bloggerportal und Heyne Verlag für die freundliche Bereitstellung dieses Rezensionsexemplars. Klappentext In der chinesischen Millionenstadt Chengdu treibt ein kaltblütiger Killer sein Unwesen, der vor 18 Jahren...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buchrezension-184-hauptmann-und-moerder/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buchrezension-184-hauptmann-und-moerder/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>13 tools to use for DevSecOps automation</title>
        <description>
          
          In 2021 there have been 25% more ransomware attacks than in 2020––and these are only the publicized attacks. No doubt, it’s becoming more necessary to secure your organization and software products against cyber threats and security vulnerabilities. Software security issues include bugs, authentication, unsecured authentication, data exposure, libraries with vulnerabilities,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/devsecops-tools/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/devsecops-tools/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chatter von Ethan Kross</title>
        <description>
          
          Titel: Chatter. Die Stimme in deinem Kopf Autor: Ethan Kross Verlag: btb Erschienen: Februar 2022 Seitenanzahl: 304 Bewertung: 🌕🌕🌕🌗🌑 Danke an Random House Bloggerportal und btb Verlag für die freundliche Bereitstellung dieses Rezensionsexemplars. Klappentext Der renommierte Psychologe Ethan Kross verschränkt für sein international vielbeachtetes Buch seine eigenen bahnbrechenden Forschungsergebnisse aus...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buchrezension-chatter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buchrezension-chatter/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Visual Studio Code setup for technical writing</title>
        <description>
          
          I write in Markdown pretty much every day, either personal blog posts or docs at my day job as a Technical Writer. In the past year, I’ve customized my writing workspace in Visual Studio Code to make writing more efficient and pleasant. In this post, I’ll share with you my...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/vscode-setup-for-technical-writing</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/vscode-setup-for-technical-writing</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to automate every step of an incident response workflow</title>
        <description>
          
          Cyberincidents (like cyber crime, IT failure/outage, and data breaches) are the number one threat of large and small companies. Now imagine your company is hit by a data breach. One moment you’re minding your business as usual, the next you notice unusually high outbound traffic, some changes in important files,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/automated-incident-response/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/automated-incident-response/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Im Auftrag der Toten von Axel Petermann</title>
        <description>
          
          Titel: Im Auftrag der Toten Autor: Axel Petermann Verlag: Heyne Erschienen: September 2021 Seitenanzahl: 384 Bewertung: 🌕🌕🌕🌕🌑 Danke an Random House Bloggerportal und Heyne Verlag für die freundliche Bereitstellung dieses Rezensionsexemplars. Klappentext Ein Mann wird wegen Mordes an seiner reichen Tante zu lebenslanger Haft verurteilt – doch die Ermittlungsunterlagen offenbaren...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buchrezension-im-auftrag-der-toten/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buchrezension-im-auftrag-der-toten/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is hyperautomation and how it will transform business operations</title>
        <description>
          
          Are you trying to convince your manager to invest (more) in automation? Or are you the manager who went a bit over budget with automation tools and you’re wondering if it was worth it? Or maybe you’re just exploring the vast space of workflow automation tools and wondering: “Is this...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/hyperautomation-trends/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/hyperautomation-trends/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rituale von Christine Dohler</title>
        <description>
          
          Titel: Rituale. Wie sie unser Leben stärken Autor: Christine Dohler Verlag: Goldmann Erschienen: September 2021 Seitenanzahl: 224 Bewertung: 🌕🌕🌗🌑🌑 Danke an Random House Bloggerportal und Goldmann Verlag für die freundliche Bereitstellung dieses Rezensionsexemplars. Auf der Suche nach Bücher über Achtsamkeit und Meditation, habe ich Christine Dohlers Buch gefunden. Die Autorin...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buchrezension-rituale/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/buchrezension-rituale/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to write in accessible language</title>
        <description>
          
          As a technical writer creating tutorials and courses for users of all levels, I’m constantly re-evaluating my content, looking for ways to make it more accessible and easy to understand. I had one such oportunity yesterday, when I attended the workshop Improve Your Writing Using Accessible Language, held by Amy...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/accessible-language/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/accessible-language/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to synchronize data between two systems (one-way vs. two-way sync)</title>
        <description>
          
          Whether you work in marketing, sales, or data engineering, you most likely use several apps or services for collecting and storing data from different sources. To boost productivity and reduce errors, you can automate various tasks in each system – from lead capturing in CRMs to e-commerce workflows and data...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/data-sync-workflows/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/data-sync-workflows/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 ways to keep your skills fresh after finishing a coding bootcamp</title>
        <description>
          
          One year ago at this time, I was nervously making last-minute changes to slides for a presentation. Not just any presentation, but one of my final project for the Data Science Bootcamp at SPICED Academy, where I spent three full months learning about different machine learning algorithms and Python best...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/keep-your-skills-fresh-after-coding-bootcamp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/keep-your-skills-fresh-after-coding-bootcamp/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
